Curriculum Vitae Jeremy D. Castagno

1564 McIntyre St., Ann Arbor, MI 385-204-6580

idcasta@umich.edu

I Website: https://ieremybyu.github.io

Personal Website: https://jeremybyu.github.io/

SUMMARY

I am in my second year pursuing a Ph.D. in Robotics as the University of Michigan specializing in autonomy & safety for Unmanned Aerial Systems (UAS). My work focuses on emergency landing for UAS by helping augment decision making capabilities through machine learning and multi-modal data fusion. My B.S. is in Chemical Engineering from Brigham Young University (BYU) with minors in Computer Science and Mathematics. I previously worked for Valero Energy Corporation as a process control engineer where I provided operation support and helped design and certify safety systems. While I studied at BYU I worked part time as a Research Assistant for a group called PRISM or Process Research and Intelligent System Modelling (http://apm.byu.edu/prism). My research there focused on real time model predictive control and parameter estimation. My area of expertise is in machine learning, modelling physical systems, and developing robust control strategies.

RELATED EXPERIENCE

Valero Energy Corporation, Memphis, TN Process Control Engineer

May 2013- October 2015

Daily control systems support for operation of multiple process units.

Reviewed and verified several safety systems through simulation and creation of detailed test plans. Lead gasoline blending control system upgrade while incorporating advanced process control with an estimated savings of 2 MM/yr.

Systems administrator of workstations, servers, and firewalls for the Process Control Network.

Brigham Young University PRISM, Provo, UT **Research Assistant**

August 2012- April 2013

Assisted graduate research and publication of Moving Horizon Parameter Estimation (MHE) of UAV's. Developed and implemented real time mixed-integer nonlinear programming control of a laboratory benchmark system utilizing MATLAB.

Programmed an interface (C++) between MATLAB and a laboratory control system while documenting all features clearly.

Valero Energy Corporation, San Antonio, TX Economics & Process Optimization Intern

April 2012- August 2012

Performed a thorough engineering statistical analysis of corporate gasoline blend models. These models are used in predicting gasoline properties and are executed in planning for several oil refineries. Identified model weaknesses and implemented improvements resulting in a 50% increase in model accuracy.

EDUCATION

M.S. Robotics August 2016-April 2018

University of Michigan

GPA: 3.87

B.S Chemical Engineering Brigham Young University

August 2006-April 2013

GPA: 3.73

Minors: Computer Science (GPA: 4.0), Mathematics (GPA: 3.85)

PROFESSIONAL SERVICE AND MEMBERSHIPS

International Society of Automaton Member (ISA)

COMMUNITY SERVICE

Study Abroad Engineers Without Borders, Cusco, Peru & Provo, Utah August 2011-May 2012 Organized a multi-discipline engineer team creating low cost water filters.

Designed, created, and distributed multiple engineering projects in rural villages.

Volunteer Representative, India

July 2008 – July 2010

Served as missionary for The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints Coordinated efforts of sixteen representatives as zone leader

HONORS AND AWARDS

BYU Alvina Soffel Barrett Scholarship 2011 - 2013 BYU General Engineering Scholarship 2010 - 2011

PEER REVIEWED JOURNAL PUBLICATIONS

- 1. Castagno, J. and Atkins, E. M., Automatic Classification of Roof Shapes for Multicopter Emergency Landing Site Selection, AIAA Conference. **Submitted**
- Sun, L., Castagno, J., Hedengren, J. D., and Beard, R. W., Parameter Estimation for Towed Cable Systems Using Moving Horizon Estimation, IEEE Transactions on Aerospace and Electronic Systems, in press, 2014. <u>Preprint</u>